(
"ai_sub_version": "3.3.0",
"generated_at": "2026-07-16T23:32:24.816334",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Lazy Dog Night! INUGAMI KORONE 7th Anniv. LIVE
Yeah! Hehehe...
One, two, check, check, check, check, check, check, yo
Vショウ、クローVショウ
V-show, Claw V-show
Uh, huh
Yeah! Haha
Grateful Days
Come on, come on, yo
Oh, 脳天気よ
Oh, carefree...
脳天気よ 脳天気よですよ
...carefree, carefree indeed!
Zeebra, yeah
How's show?
Dragon Ash show
Come on
Come on, yeah
Oh, oh, let's go, yo
Turn up radio そう 今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up radio, I can hear it again today
風に揺られ流れる Stereo
Flowing stereo swaying in the wind
肩で刻む 軽快な Rhythm
A light rhythm carved in my shoulder
想いをのっけて届けるよ Rhyme
I'll put my thoughts into it and deliver the rhyme
よく晴れた空の真下
Under the clear sunny sky
僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
We aimed for a distant future
Master key 握り締め出発
Clutching the master key, we departed
雑踏の中 Kick down 一発
Kick down once in the middle of the crowd
今思う闘いの日々
Thinking of the days of struggle now
感謝することに溢れだす慈悲
The mercy that overflows whenever I feel gratitude
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
The defensive battle where we sharpened our skills
今なお続くここは最前線
It still continues here on the front lines
父から得た揺るぎない誇り
The unshakable pride I got from my father
母がくれた大きないたわり
The great kindness I received from my mother
キミにもらう温かいぬくもり
The warm affection I receive from you
明日への糧に生き抜くために
To live on as sustenance for tomorrow
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it, yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when skies are gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
俺は東京生まれHIP HOP育ち
I was born in Tokyo, raised on hip hop.
悪そうな奴は大体友達
Most of the bad-looking guys are my friends.
悪そうな奴と大体同じ
I'm pretty much the same as those bad-looking guys.
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
Walking the back alleys, I've watched this city.
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期も早々に
Shibuya, Roppongi... Yeah, early on in my youth,
これにゾッコンに
I fell madly in love with this.
カバンなら置き放してきた高校に
I left my bag behind at high school,
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
and really caused trouble for my parents.
だが時は経ち今じゃ雑誌のカバー
But time has passed, and now I'm on magazine covers.
そこらじゅうで幅きかす DON DADA
Making my presence felt everywhere, the Don Dada.
マイク掴んだらマジでNo.1
Once I grab the mic, I'm truly number one.
東京代表トップランカーだ
Representing Tokyo, a top ranker.
そうこの地この国に生を授かり
Yes, blessed with life in this land, this country,
Jahに無敵のマイク預かり
entrusted by Jah with an invincible mic.
仲間たち親たちファンたちに今日も
To my friends, my parents, and my fans, today too,
感謝して進む荒れたオフロード
I show my gratitude as I trek down this rough off-road.
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky is gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
日出ずる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
Born and raised in the Land of the Rising Sun,
今こうして踏みしめる大地
now we stand firmly on this earth.
常に開く新しいPage
Always turning to a new page,
旅に出ようそれぞれのStage
let's set off on our respective stages.
ここに綴る喜びと感謝
Writing down our joy and gratitude here,
共に奏でる真の理解者
playing together as true companions.
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Depicting the times without hiding a thing,
Pressureはねのけて乱反射
brushing off the pressure and reflecting it away.
注ぎ込もう溢れ出す感情
Let's pour in these overflowing emotions.
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
Never letting our love run dry.
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
Diving into the battlefield without flinching,
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
the lily crest blooms, never withering.
やさしい風ぬける昼下がり
An early afternoon with a gentle breeze blowing through.
虹がのぞいたこんな雨上がり
A rainbow peeked out after a rain like this.
陽の光映した水たまり
A puddle reflecting the sunlight.
日々の喜びここに讃美
Praising our daily joys right here.
この胸の高鳴りを
The throbbing in my chest,
歌にのせて
I put it into song.
日々ここにあるもの
The things that exist here day by day,
この手に感じて
I feel them in my hands.
I got sound, i got feel, i got beautiful days
I got song, i got love, i got grateful days
I got it yeah
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when the sky is gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
うわあああ！
Whoaaa!
ルパン
Lupin!
ルパン三世
Lupin the Third
Let me show you my everything 夢のこのファンタジー見てな
Let me show you my everything, check out this dream fantasy!
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time)
Now is the time to run! (It's show time!)
そこで見ててよワンマンショー これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
Watch my one-man show from there, this level of ordeal isn't enough!
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want isn't material things, I steal your heart!
Listen! Party people! 僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
Listen! Party people! I'm running through life at breakneck speed,
まるでスキーの直滑降 核弾頭 決めたことには頑固
like a straight downhill ski run. A warhead, stubborn once I've decided!
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない ここはステージ遠慮はいらない
I don't know how to live life slowly. This is the stage, no holding back!
やることはやりますわ 高みの山目指せ
I'll do what needs to be done. Aim for the highest peak!
Put your hands up in the air!
それを見つめる君はセクシー 甘くトロけるまるでチェルシー
Watching that, you are sexy, melting sweetly like a Chelsea candy.
手櫛で髪掻き上げる様
The way you run your fingers through your hair,
僕にとっての女王様
My queen...
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
I'll hold you tight tonight...
and 熱い唇をいただく
and take your hot lips...
そして何よりも欲しいのよ
And most of all, I want...
あなたの心 狂おしいほど
your heart, so much it drives me crazy.
It's a party night
Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance
everybody, don't stop dancing.
Let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even on a thorny road,
凍てつく夜だろうが
even on a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ 君と二人で
the impossible will become possible, with just the two of us.
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー！
Lupin The Fire!
だからそうだから
That's why, yes, that's why,
誰も手にした事ないお宝もらう
I'll take the treasure no one has ever held.
狙った獲物は逃がさない
I won't let my targeted prey escape,
それがなんだろうと大泥棒
no matter what it is, I'm a master thief.
先の先まで計算
Calculating way ahead,
瞬時にひらめく名案
a brilliant idea flashes instantly.
そして「あっ!」と思ったらもう居ない
And once they think "Ah!", I'm already gone.
もはや芸術ばりの盗みの美学
A theft aesthetic that is practically art.
Put your hands up in the air!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Look at this fantasy of dreams.
今こそ走る時なんだ
Now is the time to run.
It's show time!
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me perform my one-man show right there.
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
An ordeal like this is not enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want is not a thing.
I steal your heart
絶対逃がさん！
I'll definitely never let you escape!
無駄な抵抗はやめて大人しくお縄につけ！ ルパン！逃がさんぞ！
Stop your useless resistance and surrender quietly! Lupin! You won't escape!
誰かが居ないと張り合い無い
If there's no one around, it's no fun competing.
相手が居てこそ間違い無い
Having a rival makes it real, no doubt.
身近にゃ素敵なライバル
A wonderful rival close by,
競い合い互いにハイになる
competing makes us both get fired up.
ファイナルステージだ天王山
It's the final stage, the decisive battle,
お前と勝負の演奏さ
the performance of our showdown.
マジで今夜はサシで
Seriously, tonight it's one-on-one,
どっちが勝っても文句はナシで
no complaints no matter who wins.
Put your hands up in the air!
ワルサー使いこなす僕はワルさ
Handling my Walther, I am bad.
曲がったこと嫌いプラスアルファ
Hating crooked things, plus a little extra.
ラップマスター ジェダイも目じゃない
A rap master, even Jedi can't compete.
しかし可愛い女にも目がない
But I also have a weakness for cute girls.
Oh baby それは演技？ or 本気？
Oh baby, is that acting or for real?
僕は君に一本気
I'm single-minded for you.
一本道走り続けます
I'll keep running down this single path.
空へ飛ばす 今日から明日
Flying into the sky, from today to tomorrow.
It's a party night
Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance
everybody, don't stop dancing.
Let's go just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even on a thorny road,
凍てつく夜だろうが
even on a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ
the impossible will become possible,
君と二人で
with just the two of us.
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー！
Lupin The Fire!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Look at this fantasy of dreams.
今こそ走る時なんだ
Now is the time to run.
It's show time!
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me perform my one-man show right there.
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
An ordeal like this is not enough.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want is not a thing.
あんたのハート
Your heart!
愛すべき仲間や家族がいる
I have lovable friends and family,
信念やプライドを曲げずに貫くべし！
you should carry out your beliefs and pride without bending them!
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー！
Lupin The Fire!
Let me show you my everything
眩しい眼差しをうけて
Receiving your dazzling gaze,
君のために今日を捨てるよ
I'll cast aside today for you.
It's show time!
世界で一人の最愛の君に
To you, my only beloved in the world,
君自身に気持ち伝えたいよ
I want to convey my feelings to you yourself.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want is not a thing.
あなたのハート
Your heart!
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually a goofy comic character,
やるときゃ誰より真剣で
but more serious than anyone when it counts.
頼りになるいざという時
Reliable in times of need,
こうなりたい誰が見ても素敵
I want to be like that, looking great to anyone.
知性備えたスーパーマン
A Superman equipped with intelligence,
横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
and at his side, as always, a Superwoman.
残り二小節ラストスパート
Last spurt with two measures remaining,
憧れの男 Lupin The Third!
of the man I admire: Lupin The Third!
獲物は確かに頂いたぜ
I have indeed taken the prize.
はい！ ということで
Yes! So with that,
「Grateful Days」と「ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー」を、2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
you just heard "Grateful Days" and "Lupin The Fire", two songs in a row!
「Grateful Days」はですね、
"Grateful Days" is,
えーっと、男性2人と女性1人の曲なんですけど、
well, a song for two males and one female, but...
女性のところはね、絶対アズちゃんが良いということで、アズちゃん。
for the female part, I absolutely wanted Azu-chan, so Azu-chan did it.
で、ラップパートはもうノエルちゃんの顔しか浮かばなかったので、ノエルちゃんにお願いしました！
And for the rap part, only Noel-chan's face came to mind, so I asked Noel-chan!
二人ともありがとう！
Thank you both!
でね、ルパンの映像が流れて、みんなびっくりしたんじゃない？ ころねもびっくりした。
And with the Lupin video playing, everyone was surprised, right? Korone was surprised, too.
で、今日のハッシュタグは、もうね、7周年だって。すごいよね！
And today's hashtag is... it's already the 7th anniversary. That's amazing, right?
この上のハッシュタグ、「#戌神ころね7周年」で、ぜひいっぱい呟いてください。
Please tweet a lot with this hashtag above, "#InugamiKorone7thAnniversary".
スクショも大丈夫だよ！
Screenshots are also okay!
ね、ここのステージ、なんか、今日は違った感じだけど、
And this stage here... it feels a bit different today, but...
ここはどこなんでしょうか？
where could this be?
どこ？
Where?
イヌバレー！
Inu Valley!
素敵。
Lovely.
今日はイヌバレーから、すべてお送りしますので、よろしくお願いします。
Today, we will be broadcasting everything from Inu Valley, so please look forward to it.
って思ったんだけどさ、なんか、画面小さくない？って思ったよね、リスナーさんもね。
And speaking of that, don't you think the screen is a bit small? I bet you listeners thought so too, right?
ころねもちょっと思ったので、ちょっとね、
Korone thought so too, so...
あ、ちょっと待って！
Ah, wait a minute!
なんか、縮まってる！縮まってる！
Wait, it's shrinking! It's shrinking!
やめて！やばい、やばい！
Stop! Oh no, oh no!
潰れちゃうよ、これ。
I'm gonna get crushed!
ちょっと押して、今は令和なのでね、画面を広く使いたいので、
Let me push them back. We are in the Reiwa era now, so I want to use a wider screen...
あっち行け！
Go away!
もうちょっとあっち行け！
Go away a bit more!
もうちょい！
A bit more!
オッケー、オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay, okay.
こっちは？
What about this side?
あっち行け！
Go away!
あれ？そんなにころねと居たいの？おいで。
Oh? Do you want to stay with Korone that much? Come here.
本当に来るなよ！本当に来るなよ！
Don't actually come! Don't actually come!
いっくよ、早く
Let's go, hurry!
いた
Found it.
あ、いたね。何だったんだろうね。
Ah, there it is. Wonder what that was.
ということで
So...
あ、なんか
Ah, something...
なんか落ちてきたよ！
Something is falling!
花びらかな？これ。
Is this a petal?
あっちから降ってきた？
Did it fall from over there?
ちょっと行ってみよう！
Let's go check it out!
さくら
[Title: Sakura]
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering of the cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and...
君の声が戻ってくる
...your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The fleeting scent from when the wind blew through your hair, fluttering it,
淡い香り戻ってくる
comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururira, hyururira...
ヒュルリーラ
Hyururira...
さくら散りだす 思い出す 意味なく
The cherry blossoms start to scatter, and I remember for no reason.
灯りだす あの頃また気になる
Lights turn on, and again I think about back then.
変わらない香り 景色 風
The unchanging scent, the scenery, the wind...
違うのは君がいないだけ
...the only thing that's different is that you're not here.
ここに立つと蘇る
When I stand here, it all comes back to life,
こみ上げる記憶 読み返す
the memories well up, and I re-read them.
春風に舞う長い髪 たわいないことでまた騒いだり
Long hair fluttering in the spring wind, acting silly and having fun.
さくら木の真下 語り明かした
We talked all night long beneath the cherry blossom trees,
思い出は俺 輝いた証だ
those memories are my shining proof.
さくら散る頃 出会い別れ
When the cherry blossoms scatter, there are meetings and departures,
それでも ここまだ変わらぬままで
yet this place still remains unchanged.
咲かした芽 君離した手
The buds we bloomed, your hand that let go,
いつしか別れ 交わしたね
and before we knew it, we parted ways.
さくら舞う季節に取り戻す
I'll take back those times in the season of scattering blossoms,
あの頃そして君呼び起こす
and call you back to life.
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter...
記憶舞い戻る
...the memories return.
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter...
記憶舞い戻る
...the memories return.
気が付けばまたこの季節で
Before I know it, it's this season again,
君との思い出に誘われ<,s:
enticed by my memories of you.
心の扉たたいた
I knocked on the door of my heart,
でも手をすり抜けた花びら
but the petals slipped through my hand.
初めて分かった 俺若かった
For the first time I understood, I was young,
この場所来るまで 分からなかったが
I didn't understand until I came to this place.
此処だけは今も何故
Why, only in this place even now,
定めのように香る風
does the wind smell like destiny?
暖かい陽の光がこぼれる
The warm sunlight spills down,
目を閉じればあの日に戻れる
if I close my eyes, I can go back to that day.
いつしか君の面影は
Before I knew it, your trace...
消えてしまうよ何処かへ
...disappears to somewhere.
あの日の以来 景色変わらない
Since that day, the scenery hasn't changed,
散りゆく花びらは語らない
the scattering petals do not speak.
さくらの下に響いた 君の声今はもう
Your voice that echoed beneath the cherry blossoms is now no more...
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering of the cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and...
君の声が戻ってくる
...your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The fleeting scent from when the wind blew through your hair, fluttering it,
淡い香り戻ってくる
comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururira, hyururira...
そっと僕の肩に
A petal of a flower gently falls on my shoulder...
舞い落ちたひとひらの花びら
...as it flutters down.
手に取り 目をつむれば
When I take it in my hand and close my eyes,
君が傍にいる
you are by my side.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering of the cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and...
君の声が戻ってくる
...your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing,
あの頃のままで
just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The fleeting scent from when the wind blew through your hair, fluttering it,
淡い香り戻ってくる
comes back to me.
二人約束した
Just like back then,
あの頃のままで
when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururira, hyururira...
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter...
記憶舞い戻る
...the memories return.
花びら舞い散る
The petals scatter...
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
Cherry blossom petals dance and scatter, memories dance and return.
花びら舞い散る
Cherry blossom petals dance and scatter.
人はこれって時にどうしても
I wonder why people always say,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
"if only we could turn back the hands of time..."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
yet it's impossible and it always has been.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
Life can get tough, so we might as well enjoy it.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future is surely deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is so boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
So let's hop in a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler.
箱の中の猫を思っても
Even if we think about the cat in the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret burns our chests,
いつもあの猜疑心が遮るんだわ
and that doubt always gets in the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been like that, so we might as well enjoy it.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future is surely deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is so boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
So let's hop in a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler.
どこをどうやってもね
No matter what we do where,
時間ってのは戻せない
time cannot be turned back.
レンズ越し未来にめがけて
Aiming through the lens to the future,
ピースサイン伝えてる 今のところいい調子
I'm sending a peace sign, so far so good.
青春の1ページも
Even a page of youth
たったの1ページで
is just one page,
自慢の人生のハイライトも 一夜きりの Tweet の buzz みたい
and the highlight of my proud life
is like a one-night Tweet buzz.
君と出会った日のことを覚えてるよ
I remember the day I met you.
イヤフォン垂らしてこの曲をきいていたよ
I was listening to this song with earphones dangling.
あれから数えて今日は何年目!?
Counting from then, what year is it today!?
今じゃ足跡どこも残るから これは歌詞カード
Since footprints remain everywhere now, this is a lyric card.
載せず鍵かけておこう ＃％＆＄”＝〜 ほにゃららむにゃらこぽんぽこ
Let's keep it locked up, #%&$~ gibberish.
ほらね、聴き取れない!!
See? You can't hear it!
皆いつもくよくよ悩み
Everyone is always worrying,
締め切りに追われ歴史を作り
chased by deadlines, making history,
弱さを無理やりごまかし
forcibly cheating our weakness.
君の芝生は緑 青じゃなくていい
Your lawn is green, it doesn't have to be blue.
アイドル撮られちゃった真冬の空に
The idol got photographed in the midwinter sky,
政治家ぶれてブレちゃった帰り道
and the politician shook and faltered on the way home,
とうちゃんローン組んだみはてぬ先
Dad took out a loan for an endless future.
でも時は全部を流して
But time washes everything away.
人はこれって時にどうしても
I wonder why people always say,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
"if only we could turn back the hands of time..."
残誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
yet it's impossible and it always has been.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
Life can get tough, so we might as well enjoy it.
きっと先は深くて不安定
The future is surely deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃつまんないね
but being well-behaved is so boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
So let's hop in a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a traveler.
俺ってやつはいつも気づいた時は手遅れ
A guy like me is always too late when he realizes,
絵空事ばかりうつつ抜かして
losing myself in nothing but fantasies,
大事な人すら救えない
unable to save even the people who matter.
だからこんな歌で自分に言い聞かして
So I tell myself with a song like this.
あの時 あいつは多分 気を使って
Back then, he was probably being considerate,
とくに顔色変えず 何もないふり
not changing his expression, pretending nothing happened.
なんで言わないんだって ムカついてもね
Even if I get annoyed wondering why he didn't say anything,
やさしさからきてたなら しょうがないね
if it came from kindness, it can't be helped.
願わくばディスコで親父と母さんが会った日に行きたいね
Hopefully, I want to go to the day my
dad and mom met at a disco.
後ろのジョックスに酒 かけて息子じきじきにチャンス作ってやるぜ
I'll pour alcohol on the jocks in the back
and make a chance myself as their son.
どんなでかい時計だってすべてさ 始まりはこんな小さい歯車
No matter how huge a clock is, everything starts
with such a small gear.
細かいことはもういいや 疲れた
I'm done with the details, I'm tired.
別に怒ってないってさ未来は
The future says it's not particularly mad at me.
人はこれって時にどうしても
I wonder why people always say,
「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
"if only we could turn back the hands of time..."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
yet it's impossible and it always has been.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
Life can get tough, so we might as well enjoy it.
きっと先は深くて不安定
I'm sure the path ahead is deep and unstable,
でもお行儀良くちゃつまんないね
but playing by the rules is just boring.
タイムマシンに乗り込んで
Hop on the time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and if we could become travelers...
Done
yo シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて
Yo, kicking open the Chevrolet door,
街に飛び出した俺たち
we leaped out into the city streets.
暴力 酒に女 音楽
Violence, alcohol, women, music...
中指立てる大人の仮面に
flipping the bird to the masks of adults.
Oh さぁ踊ろう 「今日」という日を
Oh, come on, let's dance, taking "today"...
生き急ぐメンバー
...with the crew living life in the fast lane.
足りねぇか？ Little louder!
Not enough? Little louder!
欲望渦巻く路上が現場
The desire-swirling streets are our stage.
Yeah いつだってそうだろう？
Yeah, it's always been that way, right?
ブルハ 尾崎 永ちゃんが教科書
The Blue Hearts, Ozaki, and Yazawa were our textbooks.
くたばるまで格好つけてぇ
We wanna look cool until the day we die.
誓ったよあの放課後
We made that vow after school.
俺らピーターパン
We are Peter Pans.
「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん
We can't just say "maybe someday."
嘲笑っとる大人に言ってやるぁ
We'll show those sneering adults
人生はたったの一回だ
that you only get one shot at life.
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our hearts, that primal urge...
見て見ぬフリ No, No
...we won't turn a blind eye, no, no.
夢追い笑われ
Mocked for chasing dreams,
傷だらけでギラつく My way
covered in scars, shining on my way.
Go on! You should know
who we are
Forever Young
Hey! Just next to me from now
大切なことは
What matters most...
魂の状態
...is the state of your soul.
Forever Young
Hey! It's your turn next time from here
「あの日始めれば良かった」
"I wish I had started that day."
その次の
The next best time...
始めるべき時は今
...to start is right now!
高笑いする都会の喧騒
The roaring laughter of the city's bustle,
ウケ狙いならば振り向けんぞ
if you're just seeking attention, I won't look back.
何連呼？ 忘れろ？ 夢流した便所
Repeating what? Forget it? The toilet where dreams were flushed,
見下ろしてきやがる摩天楼
with skyscrapers looking down on us.
Oh まるで勝新みたく破天荒
Oh, wild and reckless like Shintaro Katsu,
伝説へとアテンド
attending to our legendary path.
怖にゃあ怖にゃあってその程度
Cowering "I'm scared, I'm scared" — is that all you've got?
捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Throw away your sour grapes and past glory.
永遠なんぞはねぇて
There is no such thing as eternity,
いつか天へ召され
one day we'll be called to heaven.
ペンの書き殴ったこの魂は2PACみたく
This soul scribbled in pen, like 2Pac's,
誰かの心を通過
will pass through someone's heart.
なぁ 何か忘れちゃねぇか
Hey, haven't we forgotten something?
人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Life is like a movie, everyone's an entertainer.
思い出せ思想は現実化する
Remember, thoughts manifest into reality.
誰がHighway飛ばすBentayga
Who's speeding down the highway in a Bentayga?
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our hearts, that primal urge...
見て見ぬフリ No, No
...we won't turn a blind eye, no, no.
夢追い笑われ
Mocked for chasing dreams,
傷だらけでギラつく My way
covered in scars, shining on my way.
Go on! You should know
who we are
Forever Young
Hey! 俺たちは今日だって
Hey! Even today, we are...
若気の至りのような
...still chasing dreams
夢を追いかけて来た
like the folly of youth.
Forever Young
Hey! 変わるはずなんてない
Hey! There's no way we're changing.
さぁ至ってやろうぜ！
Come on, let's reach the top!
今日は残された人生で
Today is, of the life we have left...
一番若い日だろ
...the youngest day, isn't it?
半端な覚悟ならドブに捨てな
If your resolve is half-hearted, throw it in the gutter!
往生際が悪いテメー笑い飛ばし
Laughing off your bad grace,
誇れ Better days
take pride in better days!
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet,
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで保存
we won't let it end until we burn out!
まだ終わらない保存
It's not over yet,
終わらせやしない くたばるまで保存
we won't let it end until we die!
Forever Young
もう夢を追いかけ本気になった心は
A heart that got serious about chasing dreams...
自分の指図も受けない
...won't even take orders from itself.保存
Forever Young
Hey! その思いから逃れられないなら
Hey! If you can't escape those feelings...保存
自ら向かうだけ
...then just face them yourself.
終わらせやしない
We won't let it end,
燃え尽きるまで
until we burn out!
まだ終わらない
It's not over yet,
終わらせやしない くたばるまで
we won't let it end until we die!
まだ終わらない まだ終わらない
It's not over yet, it's not over yet...
Forever Young
そう今日という日は
Yes, today is...
お前に残された人生の一番若い日
...the youngest day of the rest of your life.
マリン、来てくれてありがとう！
Marine, thank you so much for coming!
呼んでくれてありがとう！
Thank you for inviting me!
いや、マジこの「Forever Young」って曲をマリンと一緒に歌いたかったの！「Forever Young」って曲をね。
No, really, I seriously wanted to sing this song "Forever Young" with Marine!
ああ、それはマリンがおばさんにならないように？
Ah, is that so Marine doesn't become an old lady?
そう！もうフォーエバーのヤングでいようねっていうね！
Exactly! Like, "let's stay forever young," you know!
そうだね、永遠にヤングでいましょう、みんな、みんな、フォーエバーヤングで！
That's right, let's stay forever young, everyone!
悩んだー！
I was torn!
でもマリン今日はね、今日はね
But Marine today, you know, today...
え、後ろ見て？
Wait, look behind you.
演奏してくれてる...
They are performing...
気まずいよ
This is awkward.
今日はね、演奏してくれてるの、みんなが
Today, they're performing for us, everyone!
乗ってるよ、乗ってるよ
They're grooving, they're grooving!
乗ってるでしょ？ え、どの人と写真撮りたい？
They're grooving, right? Wait, who do you want to take a picture with?
え、そんな、一人だけみたいな、そんな...
Wait, just one person... that's like...
いやいや、二人選んでいい、二人選んでいい
No, no, you can choose two! You can choose two.
かわいそうじゃん、選ばれなかった人
That's so sad for the one who doesn't get chosen.
二人選ぼう、二人
Let's choose two, two of them!
俺もう、ころねすきがなんか...
I feel like the Koronesuki is...
いいよ、マリンが選ぶんだよ！
It's okay, Marine will choose!
あ、マリンが選ぶ...
Oh, Marine will choose...
そう、最初は... / 待って、あ、待って、映して後ろ
Yes, first up is... / Wait, show the ones behind us.
みんな下向いて
Everyone is looking down!
細犬さん！
Hosoinu-san!
かわいい！
So cute!
じゃあ、細犬と、まず、まず写真撮ろうか！ / かわいいよ、細犬
Then let's take a picture with Hosoinu first! / Hosoinu is cute.
こっちおいで、マリン、こっちにね / はい、細犬です！
Come here, Marine, to this side. / Yes, here is Hosoinu!
えっと、細犬はギターかな？
So, is Hosoinu on guitar?
ギターですか？細犬ちゃん
Are you on guitar, Hosoinu-chan?
ベロの色が... / かわいいね
His tongue color is... / It's cute.
乾いてる、ベロ / ベロ乾いて、澄んでるんだけど
His tongue is dry. / His tongue is dry, but it looks clear...
かわいい / 乾いてるから触らないでね
Cute. / It's dry so don't touch it!
ごめんね、いっぱい触って
Sorry for touching you so much.
え、次、誰がいい？ / かわいい、あと一人、あと一人
So, who's next? / Cute, one more, one more.
じゃあ...
Then...
太犬？ / 太犬 / 太犬だね
Futoinu? / Futoinu. / Futoinu, right.
はい、太犬はドラムです！かわいい！ / でかい！
Yes, Futoinu is on drums! So cute! / Huge!
かわいいね
So cute.
ベロの色がちょっと明るい
His tongue color is a bit brighter.
細犬より
Compared to Hosoinu's.
撮った？ / みんな撮った？ / 撮った？
Did you take it? / Did everyone get a picture? / Did you?
かわいい！ / オッケーだね / うん、オッケー
So cute! / We're good, right? / Yeah, okay.
え、じゃあ最後さ、二人とも撮ろうよ！二人でも！
Then, let's take a picture of both of us at the end! With both!
あ、そうだね、二人でも撮ろう、二人で
Oh, that's right. Let's take one with both of us.
二人で撮って
Take a picture of the two of us.
え？ちょっと...
Wait, what...?
あ、ごめんごめん！やっぱりじゃあね、やっぱり一人で撮りたいみたいだから
Ah, sorry, sorry! It seems they want to take individual pictures after all.
あ、やっぱりね！ころねすきーだもんね
Oh, of course! Since they're Koronesuki.
撮りましょうか / ころねすきー、ころさん好き？
Shall we take it? / Koronesuki, do you like Koro-san?
好き？ころさん好き？
Do you like me? Do you like Koro-san?
あ、よかった。え、マリンも好き？ / 間に入ろう
Ah, thank goodness. Wait, do you like Marine too? / Let's get in the middle.
なんでだよ！ / ころねすきーなのに、ころさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
Why?! / Even though you're a Koronesuki, how does it feel to not be able to stand next to Koro-san?
嬉しい？マリンが隣で
Are you happy Marine is next to you?
嬉しくない... / 本当は好きなんでしょ？
Not happy... / You actually like her, don't you?
やめろ！やめろよ！ / ダメ、もうダメ、帰るよ、帰るよもう
Stop it! Stop it! / No, no more, I'm going home, I'm going home now.
はい、帰ろう。はい、帰ろう
Okay, let's go. Yes, let's go back.
はい、今日はね、今日のバンドメンバーがいましたけれどですね / ええ
Yes, so we had today's band members here today, but... / Yeah.
はい、あ、マリンとも最後撮りたい / あ、とろとろ、とろー
Oh, I want to take a final photo with Marine too. / Let's take it, let's take it.
せっかくだね、Forever Youngだから今日は
Since we're Forever Young today, after all.
マイク！マイク間違えちゃってるけど / マイクね、うん、いいよいいよ
The mic! You got the mic wrong, but... / The mic, yeah, it's fine, it's fine.
でかい声で喋るな、拾うから！
Don't speak in a loud voice, it'll pick it up!
取れた？
Did you get it?
いけてる？ / 太犬！
Is it good? / Futoinu!
いい感じに撮れたね
We got a good one, right?
ありがとう、マリン！ / ありがとう
Thank you, Marine! / Thank you.
ね、ちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど / 次の曲。一人で帰れる？
Hey, I have to go because the next song is starting... / Next song. Can you go back alone?
あ、うん、大丈夫、大丈夫、大丈夫 / じゃあ...
Oh, yeah, I'm fine, I'm fine. / Then...
バンドメンバーのことよろしく / え？じゃあマリン、バイバイ！
Take care of the band members. / Eh? Okay, Marine, bye-bye!
よろしくって何よ、よろしく...
What do you mean by "take care"...
どんな曲？あ、え？みんな次の曲だよ！
What kind of song? Oh, everyone, it's the next song!
らららーらーらー おおー
La la la la la...
サボり方とか甘え方とか 逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to be spoiled,
how to run away, how to make excuses,
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた 柔らかい頭
I just finally learned it all, it's imprinted on my head.
This is some flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to look cool, how to be cocky,
how to chill out, how to age well,
脂の乗りに乗った 濁った目をした だらしない体
now I'm nailing it all, but my eyes are dead.
This is some sloppy body.
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や 叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be hated, how to be idolized,
how to tell off others, how to elegantly explain myself.
もっと覚えたいことが 山のようにある
There is so much we still wanna learn.
のびしろしかないわ
We've got nothing but potential!
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We've still got nothing but potential!
悪者扱い して来た街で
In the city I used to demonize,
悪者扱い して来た大人へ
I turn into the adult I used to demonize.
変わりゆく俺 鏡の中へ
If I question my ever-changing self inside the mirror,
尋ねても答えは yeah yeah yeah yeah
the answer is always yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
去る者は追わない 引く手は引いて
I won't run after the past, I'll retreat when necessary,
丸く収めた 軽くあしらって
I'll wrap up smoothly, I'll dodge and weave.
鏡の中で嘲笑ってるお前
And to you who's laughing through the mirror,
括れやしなかった たったの三文字で
I say I didn't sum people up to a single word!
日々重くなる足取りで 自分の歩幅で闊歩してる
Recently my stride's getting heavy,
still I'll be swaggering around on my pace.
カマす時ゃカマす 負かす時ゃ負かす / 割と適当な段取りで
I'll do it when I do it! I'll lose when I lose!
I'll go with this careless plan!
やっと分かって来たかも
I think I finally figured it out,
このポンコツの操縦の仕方
how to steer this piece of junk.
19の時の ついに来た感より もっとすがすがしい気持ち
Compared to my anxiety of when I was 19,
I feel so much more refreshed!
隅田川にかかる 勝鬨橋を渡る
I'll cross the Kachidoki Bridge,
hanging over Sumida River.
左手にスカイツリー
On my left hand, Skytree,
右手に東京タワー 俺はその真ん中
on my right hand, Tokyo Tower, and I'm in the very middle!
サボり方とか甘え方とか 逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to be spoiled,
how to run away, how to make excuses,
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた 柔らかい頭
I just finally learned it all, it's imprinted on my head.
This is some flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方...
How to look cool, how to be cocky...
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 いい年のこき方
How to look cool, how to act cocky, how to stay resolute, how to act our age...
脂の乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない身体
...with our fully ripened, cloudy-eyed, sloppy bodies.
幸せの体感速度は
The speed at which we feel happiness...
早くなるばかり
...only gets faster and faster.
傷が癒えていく速度は
The speed at which wounds heal...
遅くなるばかり
...only gets slower and slower.
他人に期待をしないのが
Not expecting anything from others...
今の俺の強み
...is my strength now.
手負いでも進める距離なら
If it's a distance we can cover even if we struggle,
行く 騙し騙し
we'll keep going, making do as we go.
身の程を知るほどに
The more I learn my place,
胸を張り いつも通り
the more I hold my head high, just like always.
デジタルな世に いい背伸び
But sometimes, stretching ourselves is fine.
やっと「大人気ない」ができる年
We're finally at an age where we can act "childish."
小さな枠組み ただの数字
A small framework is just a number.
縛られずに
Don't be bound by it...
でも腹を括り
...but brace yourself.
あの日の俺が立ち止まる
The version of me from back then stops in his tracks...
ほどにデカく聳え立つ
...before the towering monument.
隅田川にかかる
Crossing over the Sumida River,
勝鬨橋を渡る
I cross the Kachidoki Bridge.
重なるスカイツリー
Overlapping with the Tokyo Skytree...
東京タワーと真ん中の頼りない背中
...and Tokyo Tower, a fragile back in the middle.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to slack off, how to baby ourselves,
逃げ方とか 言い訳の仕方とか
how to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた
We've finally learned and acquired...
柔らかい頭
...flexible minds.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方
How to look cool, how to act cocky,
腹の据え方 いい年のこき方
how to stay resolute, how to act our age...
脂の乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらしない身体
...with our fully ripened, cloudy-eyed, sloppy bodies.
嫌われ方や 慕われ方や
How to be disliked, how to be adored,
叱り方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
how to scold, how to clash gracefully...
覚えたいことが山のようにある
There's a mountain of things we still want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
We've got nothing but room to grow!
俺たちまだのびしろしかないわ
We still have nothing but room to grow!
ばかまじめ
[Bakamajime (Damn Serious)]
くだんない話と
All this nonsense...
うざったい貴様と
...and annoying you...
なみなみの日々に注がれてく
...are poured into these overflowing days.
怠いが溢れ出していく
Laziness starts to overflow,
飯がまだ届かない
and my food hasn't arrived yet.
仕事は片付かない
My work isn't done.
うだつの上がらない 毎日にため息ばかり
I'm sighing day by day that I'm not getting anywhere.
でまたド派手にすっころび
And then I fell down again with a bang,
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
coffee spilled on my freshly washed shirt.
前のめりその姿勢だけは褒めて良し
You can praise my posture, always leaning forward,
肩落とす並木通り 増えた柄と差し色に
with my shoulders slumped in the tree-lined road with new patterns and accent colors.
嗚呼 本当嫌になる毎日だ
Ah, I'm really fed up with days like this.
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to...
嫌々早起きしたって
...or wake up early in the morning against my will...
その分素敵な何かが 訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
...doesn't mean something wonderful will come to visit.
今日もまた頑張っちゃうよな
But I keep working hard again today.
がむしゃら以外知らないから
I don't know anything but to go recklessly.
不器用で意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
May we who are clumsy, stubborn, and damn serious be blessed!
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
I put down my heavy luggage and stopped for a moment.
昨日の事なんざ忘れちまえば同じ
It's all the same if you forget about yesterday.
浴びるday light 羽根伸ばし
Relax and unwind in the light of day.
それか月夜にこっそりと吐き出してしまえば良い
Better let it out quietly in the moonlit night.
でもその前にアレとコレの話
But before that, we'll have this and that to talk about.
その為には先ずはソレを片し
First of all, we've got to do it up before we go.
って今は何時？いやその前に
What time is it? Nope, before that...
今日もなんだかんだ騒がしい毎度あり
...it's another noisy day, hey, there you go again.
1ヶ月くらい何にも
For about a month...
考えずだらだらしていたいな
...I want to be lazy without thinking of anything.
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいな
I want to rest, have fun, and sleep...
って思う日もあるけれど
...there are days when I wish I could.
やっとここまで来たんだよ
We've finally made it this far.
ここじゃ終われないんだよ
We just can't stop here.
辛い きつい もいつかは
All the hard and painful times...
笑い話にできると信じてるんだ ほら
...will be a laughing matter someday, I believe so.
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
So I keep working hard again today.
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ
I'm gonna sing for love with all my heart.
目一杯吸い込んだ空気
Breathing in all the air...
嗚呼 本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Ah, it's really a wonderful day!
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to...
嫌々早起きしたって
...or wake up early in the morning against my will...
ほんの少しの幸せに
Touching a little bit of happiness...
触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんだ
...makes me feel like everything's worth it.
明日もまた頑張ってみようか
Give it a try again tomorrow.
がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
I'm going to live recklessly.
不器用で意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
May we who are clumsy, stubborn, and damn serious be blessed!
do my thing do your thing
肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
Relax your shoulders and be flexible.
do my thing do your thing
あと1ミリ背伸び
Stretch your back a little higher.
嗚呼 本当嫌になっちゃうよな
Ah, I really hate it.
それでも今を生きている
But I'm still alive now.
不器用で意地っ張りで 馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
May you who are clumsy, stubborn, and damn serious be blessed!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable degree of perfection + a see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if I struggle, wanting to be like them
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I'll keep sinking like in quicksand
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable degree of perfection + a see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn and light a fire
君の心に落とすimagination
An imagination dropped into your heart
ギリギリでフライできず地獄送りさ
Just barely unable to fly, sent straight to hell
君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えてあろうか
Shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't fly?
それは目の前のプロップスに心揺らぎ近道した結果
It's the result of taking a shortcut, wavering before the props in front of you
誰かの後をつけてるだけだったからさ
Because you were just following in someone else's footsteps
未だわからないか 最初は気づいてた
Do you still not get it? I noticed it from the beginning
知らぬふりして自分の道だと言い聞かせた
Pretending not to know, telling yourself it's your own path
他は騙せない オリジナルを奏でないと
But you can't fool others, you have to play your own original
過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
Or your past self will drag you down, and you'll make an exit
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル
The difference between you and me is on a genetic level
俺を狂わせた父母祖父母には感謝してる
I'm grateful to my parents and grandparents who drove me crazy
さらに磨き上げた自分自身にも感謝してる
And I'm also grateful to my own further-polished self
なのになんかしてる 君差が離れてうちに
Yet, while you're doing whatever, the gap between us widens
絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
You'll feel despair and give up rapping anyway
5年後いや4年後？ これは余命宣告
Five years later, or maybe four? This is a prognosis of life expectancy
現状に満足して威張ってんの？
Are you satisfied with the status quo and acting big?
俺ら発展途上でもかっけえぞ
We are still developing, but we're cool!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable degree of perfection + a see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if I struggle, wanting to be like them
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I'll keep sinking like in quicksand
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable degree of perfection + a see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn and light a fire
君の心に落とすimagination
An imagination dropped into your heart
恋焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達
Men in love and women who leapt through time
うわべだけのお友達がお前のこと甘やかす
Superficial friends will spoil you
命削りのらりくらり情熱だけを注ぐ歌詞
Grinding away life, idly pouring only passion into lyrics
現実に頬濡らす理想たちが雨降らす
Wet cheeks in reality, ideals bringing down the rain
あれもカスでこれもカスで俺の歌詞で振り向かす
That is trash, this is trash, I'll make them turn around with my lyrics
フキになって無視したって知らぬうちに街を話す
Even if you ignore it in a huff, before you know it, it crawls through the city
体揺らし声を枯らしたって誰も聞いてない
Even if you shake your body and wither your voice, nobody is listening
導かれて聴いてみても耳は糸を引いてない
Even if guided to listen, ears aren't catching the thread
今日と明日明後日も白紙の中あさって
Today, tomorrow, and the day after tomorrow, rummaging through blank pages
思想すらも曲がってるだけど顔は笑ってる
Even thoughts are warped, yet the face is smiling
嘘だらけの肥溜めで のぼせるまで浸かって
In a cesspool full of lies, soaking until dizzy
空に祈り捧げたって変えられるのは声だけ
Even if you offer prayers to the sky, the only thing you can change is your voice
何かあれば孤独気取りむしり取るかね
If anything happens, acting lonely, plucking away money
指で擦りめくりあれば裏探すだけ
Rubbing with fingers, flipping through, just searching for the backside
歯止め効かぬ無駄な愚痴もすべて愛で砕けてる
Unstoppable useless grumbles are all shattered by love
もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない全部お前のせい
I don't want to write lyrics like this anymore, it's all your fault
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable degree of perfection + a see-through imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if I struggle, wanting to be like them
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I'll keep sinking like in quicksand
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
A reasonable degree of perfection + a see-through imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn and light a fire
君の心に落とすimagination
An imagination dropped into your heart
チチチチーム友達
Te-te-te-team friends
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Eh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム友達
North, South, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？ チーム友達
What are we? Team Tomodachi
お好み焼き 食う鶴橋
Eating okonomiyaki in Tsuruhashi
腹いっぱい
Full stomach
メシはウマい
The food is delicious
一人じゃ寂しいし
I'm lonely alone
電話きたら
If I get a call
かけ直した
I call back
すぐ行く会いに
I'll go meet you right away
T-E-A-M
T-O-M-O
D-A-C-H-I
T-E-A-M
T-O-M-O
D-A-C-H-I
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 祭り合い
Team Tomodachi, partying together
チギリカ交わし 飲んでる酒
Exchanging vows, drinking sake
契り
Pledge
契ろう
Let's pledge!
契り
Pledge
契ろう
Let's pledge!
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Eh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東
Kansai, Kanto
西 東
West, East
北 南
North, South
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達、チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何、え？
What are we, huh?
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達、チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
イェーイ！ヨーヨーヨー！
Yay! Yo, yo, yo!
ヤバい、ヤバい、カタギの人じゃないね、これ！
Whoa, whoa, we don't look like honest folks at all!
うー、うー、見てんのか、あ、ごめん、見てんのかよ！
Ooh, ooh, what're you looking at? Oh, sorry, what're you looking at?!
ヤバいじゃん！
That's crazy!
おい、ガラが悪いぞ、おい！
Hey, watch your attitude, hey!
ちょっとね、ちょっとね...
Just a little, just a little...
この帽子のせいでね、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね
Because of this cap, we look a bit like hoodlums.
うん、かっこいいじゃん！
Yeah, but it looks cool!
かっこいいよね。こんな格好いつかしてみたかったんだよ！
It is cool. I've always wanted to try this kind of style!
ていうかこれ、バチくそ高いからこれ気をつけて
By the way, this is incredibly expensive, so be careful with it.
え、本当にね、今日来たらこれ用意してあるんでって言われて、えっ？これ、な、何これ？って
Oh, seriously. Today, when I arrived, they told me, 'We have this ready for you,' and I was like, 'Huh? Wh-What is this?'
重たいでしょ？
It's heavy, right?
うん、重たい。でもかっこいい。
Yeah, it's heavy. But it's cool.
あの、ロックリーみたいになってるから今、うちら。
We're basically like Rock Lee right now.
ロックリー？！
Rock Lee?!
おもりつけてるからね、今。
Because we're wearing weights right now.
解き放たれたら、もっと動けるよね。
If we take them off, we'll be able to move much faster.
そう、外したらね。
Yeah, once we take them off.
いい感じになりますけどね。
We'll be in great shape.
え、でも、ころさん、周年おめでとうございます。
But anyway, Koro-san, happy anniversary!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
7周年だよ、ころね。
It's your 7th anniversary, Korone.
ねえ、すごい。お互い様だね。
Yeah, amazing. Same to you.
え、待って、みこちゃんの衣装見て。
Wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit.
これ、誕生日で...
This is the one from my birthday...
はいたやつね！
...that I wore!
かわいい！え、後ろも見て、後ろも。
So cute! Oh, look at the back too.
ちょっとあの、今回用意してくれたこの装飾に、なんかマッチしてて、汚いんですけど。
Well, it surprisingly matches this stage decoration they prepared for us, though it's a bit messy.
いや、めっちゃマッチしてます。
No, it matches perfectly.
え、でも、それで言うとさ、ころね、この衣装さ...
But speaking of which, Korone, that outfit...
ゲマズのイベントのやつじゃない？これ。
...isn't that the one from the Gamers event?
そう！超超超ゲマズの...
Yes! The Cho-Cho-Cho Gamers...
衣装！
...Outfit!
かわいいじゃん。
It's so cute.
みこちゃん、今日ね、これが初お披露目なんだ、この衣装の。
Miko-chan, today is actually the first time I'm revealing this outfit.
え！
What!
これで...
With this...
これで、「チーム友達」で、ちょっと初...
With "Team Tomodachi" as the first...
初お披露目しちゃったんですけど。
...the first reveal is with this song, but...
え、いいじゃん、いいじゃん！
Hey, that's fine, that's fine!
かわいい。ちょっと、ちょっと短くない？
It's cute. But isn't it a bit short?
え、そうなん。ちょっと...
Oh, is it? A little...
なんか、エッチじゃない？ちょっと。
Isn't it kind of sexy?
これめっちゃ短いんだよね、お尻。
Yeah, this is super short around the hips.
大丈夫？
Is it okay?
丸見えじゃん、これ！
It's completely visible!
こら！見せるんじゃないよ！
Hey! Don't show them!
大丈夫かな？
I wonder if it's okay.
しかもね、ころね、なんかさ、めっちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ。
And also, Korone, they're saying your chest is super tight in this.
いや、なんか、ちょっとシワができちゃってるの、パツパツで。
Yeah, there are actually some wrinkles forming because it's so tight.
弾け飛びそうだよね、なんか。
Looks like it's about to burst.
たぶんね、サイズが合ってないんだと思う。
I think the size might just be wrong.
あ、あ、でもそれぐらいがね、いいですからね。
Ah, but that makes it even better.
え、え、じゃ、写真撮ろう、写真。
Let's take a photo, a photo!
写真撮りたい！
I want to take a photo!
ちょっとアップめで撮りたいんだよな。
I want to take a close-up shot.
いいよ、いいよ、うん。
Sure, sure, yeah.
え、じゃ、しゃがもう。
Let's squat down.
しゃがむか。
Let's squat.
ヨー。
Yo.
あ、いいじゃん！
Oh, this is great!
ヨー、ヨー。
Yo, yo.
スパイダーマンみたいになっちゃった。
I ended up looking like Spider-Man.
ヨー、ヨー！
Yo, yo!
え、じゃ、サングラスもさ、取ってさ。
Hey, let's take off our sunglasses too.
あ、取るからね。
Oh, we're taking them off.
よいしょ、よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho.
ちょっと待ってね、みんなね。
Hold on a moment, everyone.
よいしょ。
There we go.
いくよ。
Here we go.
せーの、
One, two...
はい。
Say cheese.
あい、撮れた撮れた。
Alright, got it, got it.
え、アップめで撮る？
Shall we take a close-up?
アップめで撮りたい、イェーイ。
I want a close-up, yay!
あ、ちょっとカメラをね、いただきましてね。
Ah, let's grab the camera.
あ、どう？
Oh, how is it?
イェーイ！
Yay!
イェー。
Yeah.
撮れてる？
Is it taking?
「チーム友達」
Team Tomodachi.
チーム友達、チーム友達。
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi.
どこ歌ってんの。
Where are you singing?
え、でもさ、この曲さ、選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ。
But seriously, I was so happy you chose this song.
え、やっぱ「チーム友達」っていうぐらいの歌だから、友達と歌いたくて。
Well, since the song is literally called "Team Tomodachi," I wanted to sing it with a friend.
なんか、誰でもよかったんだけど、別に。友達だからみんな。
To be honest, anyone would've been fine. Since everyone is my friend.
おい！
Hey!
嘘、嘘。
Just kidding, just kidding.
特に、特にみこみこと歌いたかった。
Specifically, I really wanted to sing it with Mikomiko.
あ、ありがとう。
Oh, thank you.
「チーム友達」だから、当たり前じゃん。
We're "Team Tomodachi," of course.
「チーム友達」、イェーイ！
Team Tomodachi, yay!
え、でもちょっと、そろそろね、次の曲なんじゃないですか？
But hey, isn't it about time for the next song?
あ、そう、もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ続くのじゃよなんだけど。
Ah, yes, there is just a tiny bit more left, but...
あ、次どんな感じなの？
Oh, what's next like?
え、次はね、あの、パンツですね。
Well, next is... "Pants".
え？
Huh?
パンツ。
Pants.
え？パンツ？
Huh? Pants?
恥ずかしい。やめて、撮らないで。
How embarrassing. Stop, don't film.
待って、待って、え、パンツって、この履いてるパンツってこと？
Wait, wait, do you mean "pants" as in underwear, like the ones we're wearing?
え、みこさん履いてないの？
Wait, Miko-san, aren't you wearing any?
え？
Huh?
みこさん履いてないの？パンツ。
Miko-san, aren't you wearing pants?
安心してください、履いてますよ。
Don't worry, I'm wearing them!
履いてる？あ、よかった、じゃあ。
Are you? Ah, good then.
え、ころねはまだこれからなのよ、パンツ。
Wait, Korone, for me, "pants" is yet to come.
え？え？履いてないってこと？
Huh? Does that mean you're not wearing any?!
ころねはちょっとこれからなの。
Korone is a bit "yet to come" with it.
え？これから？
Huh? Yet to come?
これから、ごめん、みこみこ、あの、これからだから、ころね、パンツ。
From now on... sorry, Mikomiko, it's starting now, Korone's "Pants".
え、パ、パンツ？
P-Pants?
Show me!
Don't worry, don't flex! Don't worry, don't flex!
Don't worry, be naked!
But wear this pants!
Animal, naked!
Nature, naked!
People, naked!
But wear this pants!
Don't worry, don't flex! Don't worry, don't flex!
Don't worry, be naked!
But wear this pants!
No pants, no life!
No pants, no peace!
No pants, no night!
But wear this pants!
Kick, neck, kick, neck, kick, neck, kick!
KING NAKED KING
KING NAKED KING NAKED KING KING NAKED KING
KING KING
Don't worry Don't flex
Don't worry Be naked
Bow-weary PANTS
Animal naked
Nature naked
People naked
Bow-weary PANTS
Don't worry Don't flex
Don't worry Be naked
Bow-weary PANTS
You said naked I said NO
I said naked You said NO
You are wearing I say PANTS
I say wearing You say PANTS
KING NAKED KING NAKED KING
KING KING NAKED KING NAKED KING KING NAKED KING
KING KING NAKED KING NAKED KING KING NAKED KING KING
Simon push
I'm wearing pants
But I can post naked!
Ah, listen up!
キラッと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
The mouth suited with flashing canine teeth tells a story
リリカルがもくもくと充満し織り成すスモーキーなストーリー
The lyrical smoke rising and filling, weaving a smoky story
Let me see
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を抱い彷徨う
Wandering with uncertain peace and certain anxiety
お構いなきことに恐れ慄く
Trembling with fear at being completely ignored
十色の価値観 騒ぐラジカル 何がはじまる
Ten different values, a noisy radical, what is starting?
不器用な生き様に心疼く (Ah)
My heart aches for this clumsy way of living (Ah)
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ
I wonder why, surviving with lost reason
願っても願ってもなくならない
No matter how much I wish, it won't disappear
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ
I wonder why, my highly dangerous life
Do it again, do it again
Chase chase, Where is my utopia こじ開ける扉
Chase, chase, where is my utopia, forcing open the door
Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Viva, if you want to break the status quo, jump on
くしゃくしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる
Layering a scarred heart onto crumpled scrap paper
しわついたまま時を刻む (踊れ)
Ticking away time, remaining wrinkled (Dance)
数多くのお目目から逃げた Back in the day
Fleeing from countless eyes back in the day
ひた隠している ファンキーなヘッド
Keeping a funky head completely hidden
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも
Even a gift on the extension of individuality
誰かにとってはバグみたい
Might seem like a bug to someone else
伏し目をそらし 行くあてもない
Looking down, looking away, with nowhere to go
現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生
At a standstill, unable to wash away current situations or emotions
抱いても泣いても足掻いても Fall... Uhh
Holding, crying, struggling, we fall... Uhh
放浪 噛み締め 揺蕩う
Wandering, biting my lip, swaying
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
An animal taking a step forward
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Act like a big shot, way ahead, way ahead (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti- Cri-
Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over
The darkness takes over
さながら予定調和
Just like a pre-established harmony
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す Home town
Bound by newly learned despair, our hometown goes wrong before our eyes
手招く反逆のアイコン
The beckoning icon of rebellion
一抹の不安抱くも邂逅
An encounter despite carrying a sliver of anxiety
平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰頼り歩けば Dope Dope Dope
Walking under the shade, ignoring those pacified by peace, dope dope dope
What a uhm...
山積みトラブルに追い追われ多忙
Chased by a mountain of trouble, so busy
やさぐれ罵倒にはなむけ発砲 (BANG!)
A parting shot of gunfire to the corrupt abuse (BANG!)
Bang ba bang ba bang ba
ぶち抜く不条理 ヘッドばん
Smashing through the absurdity, headbang
出る杭打つのに必死なプライド
Desperately trying to hammer down the outstanding nails, pride-
塗れのエネミーに見舞う超ヤバいもん
-coated enemy is hit with something super crazy
狂った情緒で冷え切った体温
Body temperature chilled by a crazed state of mind
滾るこのエナジーは文字通りザイオン
This boiling energy is literally Zion
運命捻じ曲げるトリガー 着火する煙たい Dogs のお通りだ (Goooo!)
A trigger that twists fate, the smoky Dogs are passing through (Goooo!)
皆誰もがスペシャルな存在ってこと忘れた結果
As a result of forgetting that everyone is a special existence,
自分と違う箇所否定して突っぱねる それこそ欠陥
denying and rejecting differences; that is the true defect
たくさんの矛盾と向き合い続けて尚
Even as I continue to face countless contradictions,
一向になくならない愚かなる (Battle)
this foolish battle never goes away
悲愴 失踪 闘争 Never never end
Pathos, disappearance, struggle, never-ending
散らばる Hollow ぎらり剥き出しの
Scattered hollow, fangs bared with a flash,
牙と思惑が絡み合う
as hidden motives intertwine
消灯 深い夜と歌う
Lights out, singing with the deep night
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
An animal taking a step forward
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Act like a big shot, way ahead, way ahead (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti- Cri-
Don't panic, Go too far far far
Work like a dog 只管に磨いたジョブ
Work like a dog, a job polished mindlessly
ぼんやり未来が望遠鏡に浮かんだ今日
Today, a hazy future floated into the telescope
いつかのオメルタもスーベニア
Omerta from someday is also a souvenir
凍り付いた心を溶かす My whereabouts
Melting my frozen heart, my whereabouts
マフィオーサ 祝砲を放つ
Mafiosa, firing a celebratory shot
アイネ・クライネ・ナハトムジーク 歪んだ顔はグッバイ
Eine kleine Nachtmusik, goodbye to the distorted face
マフィオーサ 祝福の歌
Mafiosa, a song of blessing
ようやく見つけた掛け替えのない居場所
I've finally found my irreplaceable place
Say hoo! ほら一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Come on, let's dance together
Say hoo! また一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together again
Say hoo! ずっと一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together forever
ようやく気付けたふたつとない居場所
I've finally realized this one and only place
...居場所
...a place to call my own.
うわっはー！
Wahahaha!
みんなー！マフィオーサ、ライブ初お披露目、どうだったー？
Everyone! How did you like the live debut of "Mafiosa"?
ちょっと、パンツとマフィオーサで2曲続けてだったんですけど
Actually, I performed "Pants" and "Mafiosa" back-to-back,
このね、パンツっていう曲めちゃめちゃ好きで
and I really love this song called "Pants"!
あの、ずっと暇なとき、めちゃめちゃ聴いてたので、今回歌えて嬉しいのと
I used to listen to it all the time in my spare time, so I'm so glad I got to sing it,
ころねすきーにね、ピンクのパンツを履いて踊ってもらえたのが、凄く楽しかったので
and seeing the Koronesukis wearing pink pants and dancing was so much fun!
みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you all so much for dancing!
はい。でね、今回、えーとマフィオーサのライブ初お披露目をしたくて
Yes. And this time, since I really wanted to showcase "Mafiosa" live,
全部ね、ラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど
I decided to put together a setlist entirely of rap songs.
どうだったかな？
How was it?
ちょっと初めての試みだったから
Since it was my first time trying something like this,
すごいね、あの、準備段階から今日に至るまでめちゃめちゃドキドキで
I was super nervous from the preparation stage all the way up to today.
みんな楽しんでくれるかな、とか思ってたんだけど
I was constantly wondering if everyone would enjoy it.
だからね、みんなが楽しんで、ノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなと思います
So, I'd be really happy if you all had fun and got into the groove!
でね、原曲知らないよっていう方がね、えー、結構いると思うんですけど。結構はいないか、いると思うんですけど
Also, I'm sure there are quite a few people—well, maybe not that many—who don't know the original songs,
もしね、そういう方はぜひ、めちゃめちゃかっこいいのでね、全部の曲。原曲ぜひ聴いてみてください
but all of these songs are incredibly cool, so please check out the originals!
あ、最後に歌ったマフィオーサもですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲かっこいいので、ぜひみんな聴いてね！
Oh, and "Mafiosa," which I sang at the very end, has an incredibly cool original version, so definitely listen to it!
はい。ということで、今回もあります！周年グッズです！こちら！
Alright! And with that, we have them once again! Our anniversary merchandise! Here they are!
えっ、今回はですね、なんと、うすた京介先生に描き下ろししていただきました！ありがとうございます！
This time, incredibly, Usuta Kyosuke-sensei illustrated these drawings for us! Thank you so much!
1つずつ見ていきますかね
Shall we take a look at them one by one?
えー、最初はですね、YB-2、久しぶりに見ました。え、うちのブランドYB-2です
First up is... YB-2, it's been a while! Yes, our brand YB-2.
YB-2の、えー、うすた先生バージョンのね、パーカーです
It's a hoodie featuring Usuta-sensei's version of YB-2.
え、裏面にイラストがくる感じですね。で、胸元にYB-2って入ってて
The illustration is on the back. And it has "YB-2" on the chest.
腕にね、あの、ころねのモチーフの骨が入っております。これめちゃめちゃかっこいいと思うのでね
And on the sleeve, there's a bone, which is Korone's motif. I think this looks super cool,
お楽しみに！
so look forward to it!
続いてこちら
Next is this one!
こちらはですね、あの、パーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです
This is a sacoche bag featuring the same illustration as the hoodie.
ま、結構ね、なんかエキスポとかフェスとか、なんかみんなのね、イベントとかに来るときにサコッシュ使ってる人結構いたなと思って
I've noticed quite a few people using sacoches when they come to events like Expo or festivals,
ころねもサコッシュ出したい！っていうことで、サコッシュも出しました。皆さんぜひ使ってください
so I wanted to release one too! That's why we made it. Please use it!
続いてこちら
Next is this!
こちらはですね、えーと、ごめんなさいね
This one is... oh, sorry, excuse me...
え、ラップドッグキャップ！こちらはですね、えー、ひこさん先生のデザインで、あの、出させていただきました。ありがとうございます！
The Rap Dog Cap! This one is designed by Hikosan-sensei. Thank you so much!
え、ここにね、ころねの骨がクロスしてて
The bones of Korone's motif are crossed on the front,
横にまたこれ、YB-2です。これもYB-2なのでね。サコッシュと、あ、サコッシュ、あ、サコッシュもYB-2か
and on the side, it says "YB-2". Yes, this one is also YB-2. The sacoche... oh, the sacoche was YB-2 as well!
パーカーとサコッシュと帽子、え、全部YB-2のブランドでございます。よろしくお願いします
The hoodie, sacoche, and cap are all under the YB-2 brand. I hope you like them!
はい次
Okay, next!
これはYB-2じゃない、ころねのランダムラバーストラップ！
This one is NOT YB-2—it's Korone's Random Rubber Straps!
こちらはフカヒレママに描き下ろしてもらいました。ママありがとう！
These were illustrated by Fukahire-mama. Thank you, Mama!
こちらね、4種類ランダムで
There are 4 different designs available at random.
で、今回ね、ラップの曲が多かったということで、あの、ラップをしてるね、ころねのイラストもありますので
And since we had a lot of rap songs this time, there's also an illustration of Korone rapping!
ぜひ皆さん、全種類目指してよかったら買ってみてください
So if you'd like, please try to collect all the designs!
通常衣装と、え、YB-2のジャンプスーツと、ドッグ、え、グッドドッグ衣装と、ラップ衣装ですね。よかったら、はい、こちらもご検討ください
We have the default outfit, the YB-2 jumpsuit, the "Good Dog" outfit, and the rap outfit. Please check them out!
そしてフルセットの購入特典は
And the bonus for purchasing the full set is...
え、うすた先生描き下ろしのですね、ポストカード
a postcard illustrated by Usuta-sensei!
え、数量限定版もありますけれども、めちゃめちゃ、あの、用意しておりますので、あの、急がないで大丈夫です。あの、マジで結構用意したので、あの、ゆっくりご購入ください
There is a limited quantity version too, but we've prepared plenty of them, so there's no need to rush. Seriously, we have a lot in stock, so please take your time with your purchase.
はい、で、通常バージョンはね、箔押しの複製サイン入りとなっております
And the standard version comes with a foil-stamped replica signature!
はい、ということで、今回のライブもみんな、たくさん見てくれてありがとうございました！
Alright, thank you so much to everyone who tuned in to watch today's live stream!
以上、レイジードッグナイトでした！みんな本当にいつもありがとうね！
And that's all for LAZY DOG NIGHT! Thank you so much for always supporting me!
また会おう！
Let's meet again!
またねー！
See ya!
Yeah